<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<recipes_xml>
   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Family Friendly Spaghetti
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100174301
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main Course
      </category>
      <description>
      This Spaghetti recipe has been made for three generations in our family.  Some changes have appeared over the years, like the addition of the cinnamon and cumin (a tip I picked up from a caterer) and the fact that we have switched to whole grain pasta for better health and taste.  Please do not be picky about amounts.  I keep all my spaghetti spice jars in one box and just take the whole box out when I make spaghetti and throw in handfuls of this and that without measuring.  I just group the spices by lots, little bits, or pinches.  Fresh vegetables can be used diced, or hidden from the kids by blending.  The best part about this dish is that all the ingredients can be taken right from the cupboard (except the ground beef, which can be frozen) and spice mixes can be made up ahead to save time.  A packet of spice mix, a jar of home-canned tomatoes, and a fancy wooden pasta server make a beautiful housewarming gift.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Onion
Garlic
Basil
Oregano
Thyme
Sea Salt
Cumin
Cinnamon
Cayenne
      </spices>
      <source>
      My mother taught me this recipe when I moved out.  I come from a large family and she made big pots full of the stuff.  We?re not Italian, but we still love our spaghetti.
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 lbs ground beef
2 cups diced fresh vegetables like peppers, carrots, celery, or whatever (Optional)
1 Tablespoon onion powder (or a diced onion)
1 Tablespoon garlic powder (or some chopped garlic)
2 cans of diced tomatoes or one 1.5 litre jar of home-canned tomatoes
2 shakes Worcestershire sauce
1 Tablespoon brown sugar
1 Tablespoon basil
1 Tablespoon oregano
1 teaspoon thyme
1 teaspoon sea salt
pinch cinnamon
pinch cumin
pinch cayenne
one 900g package white spaghetti or two 375g packages whole grain spaghetti
3 Tablespoons extra virgin olive oil
grated old cheddar cheese (for garnish)
parmesan cheese (for garnish)
purple basil flakes (for garnish)
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Start by browning the ground beef.  (If it is still frozen, leave it in a covered low-heat pot for about 20 minutes while you do something else like chop vegetables.)  Break up the meat, but leave some chunks for pseudo-meatballs if you wish.  Mix fresh vegetables, onion and garlic with the cooked meat and saut? until tender.  (Alternately, put some tomatoes in the blender with the vegetables and spices, and blend.) Add tomatoes, Worcestershire sauce, sugar, and spices (or tomato puree) to the meat mixture and stir until it begins to boil.  Lower the heat to a simmer and cover.  Move it to a back burner to continue simmering until pasta is ready.  Cook the spaghetti (or pasta of your choice--we like spaghettini) following package directions.  After draining the cooking water from the pasta, toss in some extra virgin olive oil to keep the pasta from sticking to itself while waiting to be served.  Serve sauce with pasta, grated parmesan cheese, and grated cheddar cheese.  An extra sprinkling of dried purple basil leaves from last summer?s garden finishes the look.  Serves 8.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Baked French Toast
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      Nichealla Keath
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Breakfast Dish
      </category>
      <description>
      Delicious baked french toast smothered in cinnamon and butter.
Prepare in 15 minutes, cook for 40 minutes.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Cinnamon
      </spices>
      <source>
      Allrecipes.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Breakfast Perfection!
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 loaf French bread, cut in 1 inch slices
8 eggs
2 cups milk
1 1/2 cups half-and-half cream
2 teaspoons vanilla extract
1/4 teaspoon ground cinnamon
3/4 cup butter
1 1/3 cups brown sugar
3 tablespoons light corn syrup
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1. Butter a 9x13 inch baking dish.
2. Arrange the slices of bread in the bottom of the dish.
3. In a large bowl, beat together eggs, milk, cream, vanilla and cinnamon. Pour over bread slices, cover, and refrigerate overnight.
4. The next morning, preheat oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). In a small saucepan, combine butter, brown sugar and corn syrup; heat until bubbling. Pour over bread and egg mixture.
5. Bake in preheated oven, uncovered, for 40 minutes.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      GLaDOS Murder Cake
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100829925
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dessert
      </category>
      <description>
      A final gift from GLaDOS, this cake recipe is delicious at first
glance but quickly reveals its killer intent. Remove ingredients as necessary
to increase likelihood of human consumption. Note that it does contain
proven preservatives, deep penetration agents, and gas and odour control
chemicals that will deodorize and preserve putrid tissue.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Fish shaped ethyl benzene
Fish shaped volatile organic compounds
Volatile malted milk impoundments
Flaming rhubarb
      </spices>
      <source>
      Portal
      </source>
      <rating>
      Hot
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 18.25 ounce package chocolate cake mix
1 can prepared coconut pecan frosting
3/4 cup vegetable oil
4 large eggs
1 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips
3/4 cups butter or margarine
1 2/3 cups granulated sugar
2 cups all purpose flour
500 mL fish shaped ethyl benzene
300 g fish shaped volatile organic compounds
3 cups volatile malted milk impoundments
3 tablespoons rhubarb, on fire

Optional ingredients:
1 cup lemon juice
9 large egg yolks
12 medium geosynthetic membranes
1 cup granulated sugar
2 cups rhubarb, sliced
2/3 cups granulated rhubarb
1 tablespoon all-purpose rhubarb
1 teaspoon grated orange rhubarb
1 large rhubarb
1 cross borehole electro-magnetic imaging rhubarb
2 tablespoons rhubarb juice

Garnishes:
1 bag of fish shaped crackers
2 small bags of fish shaped candies
2 1/2 cups of fish shaped solid waste
500 g fish shaped dirt
3 3/4 cups candy coated peanut butter pieces, shaped like fish
1 package pull and peel licorice
6 cups sediment shaped sediment
1/3 cup unsaturated polyester resin
2 1/2 cups fiberglass surface resins
4 adjustable aluminum head positioners
2 slaughter electric needle injectors
1 cordless electric needle injector
1 injector needle driver
1 injector needle gun
3 Cranial caps
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Stir the cake mix, granulated sugar and all purpose flour into
a large bowl. Using the "low" setting on an electric mixer, slowly add
3/4 cup of vegetable oil, four large eggs, 1 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips,
and 3/4 cup butter or margarine. For a moister cake, add any amount of rhubarb
and exchange the four large eggs with nine large egg yolks. Then, add a cup of
lemon juice to the mix and stir thoroughly. When the mix is even, pour it into a
large 12" x 12" non-stick pan coated with fish shaped ethyl benzene. Cook for 30
minutes at 375 degrees fahrenheit. When the cake is removed from the oven, let it
cool for 45 minutes before spreading a can of prepared coconut pecan frosting on the
top. Top with fish shaped volatiele organic compounds, volatile malted milk
impoundments, and rhubarb, on fire. Add any amount of garnishes. Suggested additions
include a cordless electric needle injector, fiberglass surface resins, and anything
shaped like fish.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Russian Salad
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100820643
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Salad
      </category>
      <description>
      A salad that is sweet, salty and a bit sour. It originated in Russia, hence the name Russian salad. It is a quick and easy salad to make.
      </description>
      <spices>
      
      </spices>
      <source>
      Mother
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      4 tablespoons of Mayonnaise
1 large apple
3 hardboiled eggs
150 grams of carrot
150 grams of green peas
150 grams of pickles
150 grams of potatoes
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Steam the carrots, green peas and potato. Cut all of the vegetables (potato, pickle, green peas, and carrots) into small squares. Also cut the hardboiled eggs, along with the apple, into small squares, as you did with the vegetables. Then put all the cut eggs, apple, and vegetables in the same bowl. Add four tablespoons of Mayonnaise and mix. Leave bowl in fridge for at least half an hour before eating.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Spicy Butternut Squash Soup
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100764854
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Soup
      </category>
      <description>
      Flavour-full soup to whet the pallet. Delicious way to warm up the whole family. Thick consistency, so is very filling and appealing to those looking to use it as a lunch-time side dish. Makes 4 servings. Preparation time 10 mins, cooking time 1hr 10 mins, 90 calories per serving. Blender or food processor needed. Butternut squash is the squash with the highest carotene content, so this soup is an excellent source of Vitamin A (130%) and Vitamin C (35%).
      </description>
      <spices>
      Curry powder
      </spices>
      <source>
      SOSCuisine.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1/2 Butternut squash	500g
2 cloves Garlic, unpeeled
1 tbsp butter, unsalted	14g
1/2 onion, finely chopped	100g
1/2 tbsp gingerroot, grated	7g
1 tsp curry powder	3g
3 cups chicken broth	750ml
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1. Preheat the oven to 190C/375F.
2. Cut the squash in half lengthwise, remove the seeds and strings, and brush the halves with the oil. Add salt and pepper then place them on a baking sheet, cut side down. Put the unpeeled garlic cloves under the halves. Bake about 45-50 min until soft. Let the squash cool down then peel the skin and dice the pulp into 1,5 cm cubes. Peel the garlic and set aside with the squash.
3. Heat the butter in a pot over medium heat. Chop the onion, add it to the pot and saute 5 min, until translucent, with occasional stirring. Add the grated ginger and curry powder. Cook 1 min with stirring. Add the squash, garlic, and broth. Bring to a boil, lower the heat and simmer, uncovered, for 10 min. Let the soup cool down and pure it until smooth. If the soup is too thick, it may be thinned with additional broth.
4. Ladle the soup into bowls and serve.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Super Lemon Blueberry Muffins
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100817864
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Baked Goods
      </category>
      <description>
      This dish is a home-spun baked good for dessert,
and a favorite among the family. Each batch makes
16 muffins, with a nice and sweet topping. Very light
tasting with incredible flavor.
      </description>
      <spices>
      None
      </spices>
      <source>
      Family Recipe/Best of Bridge Cookbooks (Canadian)
      </source>
      <rating>
      High (10/10)
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      Muffins: 2 cups flour,
1/2 cup of sugar,
1 tablespoon of baking powder,
1/2 teaspoon of salt,
1 egg,
1 cup of milk,
1/2 cup of melted butter,
1 cup of blueberries,
Rind of one lemon.
Topping/Icing:
1/4 cup melted butter
1 tablespoon lemon juice
1/2 cup of sugar.
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      To make the Muffins:
Mix flour, sugar, baking powder, salt and lemon rind in large bowl.
Beat egg in medium bowl, then add milk and melted butter.
Add this to dry ingredients.
Stir until just mixed and add blueberries.
Fill greased muffin tin 2/3 full.
Bake 375 degrees for 20 minutes.

To make the topping/icing:
Combine melted butter and lemon juice in small bowl.
Put sugar in separate bowl.
Dunk tops of slightly cooled muffins in lemon butter, then sugar.

Eat while warm.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Chocolate Haystacks
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100818712
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dessert
      </category>
      <description>
      This is a combination of chocolate, coconut and rolled oats that is
very delicious when eaten. This dessert is a no bake "cookie" which means
that you don,t need an oven to prepare it. You can never just eat one.
The perfect comfort food for everyone.
      </description>
      <spices>
      None
      </spices>
      <source>
      My Mom makes them
I used The Kitchen Helper for the recipe
http://kitchen-helper.com/haystack-cookie-recipes.html
      </source>
      <rating>
      None
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 cups of Sugar
1/2 cup of milk
1/2 cup butter
2/3 cup cocoa
1/4 teaspoon salt
i teaspoon vanilla
3 cups rolled oats
1 1/4 cup coconut
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Before you start though make sure you have some wax paper or
parchment paper to lay the cookies out on. They mixture cools quickly
so you have to work quickly.
In a large saucepan add the sugar and other wet ingredients and stir
frequently and bring to a boil. Reduce heat to medium and boil for 2
minutes. Turn off the heat and stir in rolled oats and coconut, mix
until all the rolled oats and coconut are covered with the chocolate
mixture.
Now working quickly, spoon piles onto the wax or parchment paper
dipping the spoons in water to prevent sticking.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Vegan Banana Muffins
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100823785
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Breakfast
      </category>
      <description>
      This Vegan Banana Muffin recipe is a delicious breakfast or snack that is both wholesome, healthy, and delicious. A variation of this recipe is to add 1/2 cup of semi-sweet chocolate chips before baking. If you don't have extra bananas, add more sugar and oil. If you don't have cardamom, just add more cinnamon. Remember not to over cook.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Cinnamon
Cardamom Powder
      </spices>
      <source>
      Food.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      4 Ripe Bananas
1/2 cup brown sugar or 1/2 cup pure maple syrup
1/2 cup vegetable oil
1 teaspoon cinnamon
1 teaspoon cardamom powder
3/4 teaspoon salt
1 cup whole wheat flour
1 1/2 cup white flour
1 teaspoon baking powder
1 teaspoon baking soda
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Preheat oven to 350??F. Grease or place cups in tin for 12 muffins. Mash bananas in a bowl. Add oil, sugar or maple syrup, salt, cinnamon and cardamon and mix. Add flours, baking powder and baking soda and mix. Spoon into muffin tins and bake for 20-25 minutes until muffins are done and slightly browned on top.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Carrot Cake
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100822626
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Desert
      </category>
      <description>
      "This rich and moist spice cake, full of grated carrot and toasted nuts, has great flavour,
especially when covered with a tangy and sweet flavoured cream cheese frosting.
The interesting part is that while those pretty orange flecks of grated carrot give the Carrot Cake colour and texture,
along with sweetness and moisture, its' flavour is almost indistinguishable."
      </description>
      <spices>
      Cinnamon
      </spices>
      <source>
      joyofbaking.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 cup (100 grams) pecans or walnuts
3/4 pound (340 grams) raw carrots (about 2 1/2 cups finely grated)
2 cups (260 grams) all-purpose flour
1 teaspoon baking soda
1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 1/2 teaspoons ground cinnamon
4 large eggs
1 1/2 cups (300 grams) granulated white sugar
1 cup (240 ml) safflower, vegetable or canola oil (or other flavourless oil)
2 teaspoons pure vanilla extract
Cream Cheese Frosting:
1/4 cup (57 grams) unsalted butter, room temperature
8 ounces (227 grams) cream cheese, room temperature
2 cups (230 grams) confectioners (powdered or icing) sugar, sifted
1 teaspoon (4 grams) pure vanilla extract
1 teaspoon finely grated lemon zest (outer yellow skin)
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Carrot Cake:
Preheat oven to 350 degrees F (180 degrees C) and place rack in center of oven. Butter or spray two - 9 x 2 inch (23 x 5 cm)
cake pans and line the bottoms of the pans with a circle of parchment paper.
Toast the pecans or walnuts for about 8 minutes or until lightly browned and fragrant. Let cool and then chop coarsely.
Peel and finely grate the carrots. Set aside.
In a separate bowl whisk together the flour, baking soda, baking powder, salt, and ground cinnamon. Set aside.
In bowl of electric mixer (or with a hand mixer), beat the eggs until frothy (about 1 minute). Gradually add the sugar
and beat until the batter is thick and light coloured (about 3 - 4 minutes). Add the oil in a steady stream and then beat in the vanilla extract.
Add the flour mixture and beat just until incorporated. With a large rubber spatula fold in the grated carrots and chopped nuts.
Evenly divide the batter between the two prepared pans and bake 25 to 30 minutes or until a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean.
Remove from oven and let cool on a wire rack. After about 5 -10 minutes invert the cakes onto the wire rack, remove the pans and parchment paper,
and then cool completely before frosting.
To assemble: place one cake layer, top side down, onto your serving plate. Spread with about one third of the frosting.
Gently place the other cake, top of cake facing down, onto the frosting, and spread the rest of the frosting over the top and sides of the cake.
If desired, press toasted and finely chopped nuts on the sides of the cake and decorate the top of the cake with marzipan carrots (see below).
Cover and refrigerate any leftovers.
Serves 10 - 12.
Cream Cheese Frosting:
In bowl of electric mixer (or with a hand mixer), beat the cream cheese and butter,
on low speed, just until blended with no lumps. Gradually add the sifted powdered sugar and beat, on low speed,
until fully incorporated and smooth.  Beat in the vanilla extract, and lemon zest.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Yellow Daal (Indian Split Pea Soup)
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100704690
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Side dish
      </category>
      <description>
      An Americanized version of the Indian dishes Masoor Dal 	and Chana Dal. This dish uses Split yellow peas as opposed 	to split lentils or split chickpeas. Fairly high in 	protein and carbohydrates it is also an excellent source 	of B-vitamins as well as Folate.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Turmeric
Garlic
Asafoetida (can replace with garlic powder)
Coriander seeds
Cayenne
Cumin Seeds
      </spices>
      <source>
      Modified Internet Recipe
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium-High
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1c split yellow peas - soaked for an hour
1/4c canola or sunflower oil
1 med. red onion, finely chopped
5 large garlic cloves, sliced thin
3/4 tsp ground turmeric
1/2 tsp cayenne (less if not as spicy)
1/2 tsp cumin seeds
1 tsp coriander seeds, ground

Seasoning (after cooked):
1 tsp sea salt
1tbsp ghee, or butter
splash of lemon juice
1/4 cup chopped fresh cilantro
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1. Soak dal for an hour. Drain/rinse dal. Add chopped tomato and 3c of water. Boil.
2. Once boiling reduce heat to medium-low, cover, and then cook til tender (~45min-1hr)
3. Whisk the mixture and pick out tomato skins. Reduce heat to low.
4. Heat oil on high heat til it pops. Add cumin, onion. Reduce to medium heat and stir quickly until cumin turns darker brown (do not burn!). Once it is brown turn heat to low.
5. Add garlic. Wait a minute or two. Then add: coriander seeds, asafoetida, turmeric, cayenne.
6. Pour this mixture over the Dal.
7. Season with cilantro, butter, lemon juice, salt. Simmer for 5min low heat.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Goulash
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100839469
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      This is a very common meat dish in hungary, generaly using beef, as well as their most common spice, paprika. Best served with either a traditional egg dumpling called spaetzle (austrian name) or galuska (hungarian name), or plain rice. You can also do this in a slow cooker and let it cook for longer. If you like a little spice you can heat this dish up by adding some jalopeno peppers while simmering and then cut them up and mix it in individualy.
      </description>
      <spices>
      paprika
      </spices>
      <source>
      Family Recipe
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 lbs Beef (any cut will to, preferably marbled for flavor)
1 tsp salt
2 Large onions
2 Tbsp paprika (important to use a good paprika, preferably hungarian)
1/4 tsp black pepper
2 tablespoons of either lard, shortening or oil
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Cut beef into 1-inch cubes, add salt. Chop onions and brown in shortening, add beef and paprika. Add water to cover beef and let beef simmer along with salt and paprika for until tender.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Jamaican Jerk Chicken
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100280945
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      Jerk is a method of cooking meats that comes from the original inhabitants of Jamaica, the Arawaks. They roasted meats over fires of pimento wood from the allspice tree. Pimento wood gave a distinctive flavor to the meat and is still used for jerk grilling in Jamaica. Jerk marinades and rubs are often quite spicy with Scotch bonnet peppers. Recipes vary widely, but true jerk seasoning contains allspice. This recipe is for chicken, but pork, goat and even fish are also jerked.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Allspice
Black pepper
Cayenne pepper
Cinnamon
Nutmeg
Sage
Thyme
      </spices>
      <source>
      Caribbeanchoice.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Hot
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 tbs. Ground allspice
1 tbs. Dried thyme
1 1/2 tsp. Cayenne pepper
1 1/2 tsp. Freshly ground black pepper
1 1/2 tsp. Ground sage
3/4 tsp. Ground nutmeg
3/4 tsp. Ground cinnamon
2 tbs. Salt
2 tbs. Garlic powder
1 tbs. Sugar
1/4 cup Olive oil
1/4 cup Soy sauce
3/4 cup White vinegar
1/2 cup Orange juice
Juice of 1 lime
1 Scotch bonnet pepper, seeded and finely chopped
1 cup Chopped white onion
3 Green onions, finely chopped
4 Chicken breasts (6 to 8 oz) trimmed of fat
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      In a large bowl, combine the allspice, thyme, cayenne pepper, black pepper, sage, nutmeg, cinnamon, salt, garlic powder and sugar. With a wire whisk, slowly add the olive oil, soy sauce, vinegar, orange juice, and lime juice. Add the Scotch bonnet pepper, onion, and green onions and mix well. Add the chicken breasts, cover and marinate for at least 1 hour, longer if possible. Preheat an outdoor grill. Remove the breasts from the marinade and grill for 6 minutes on each side or until fully cooked. While grilling, baste with the marinade.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Phytoplankton Flambe
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100710716
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Appetizer
      </category>
      <description>
      Phytoplankton Flambe is an extremely rare dish that is generally not made in today's society,
and has never been made before. This dish would be very popular in coastal communities if they made it.
Since it has been criticized, at times, of not having enough paprika, this appetizer is not well-recieved,
internationally. An international delicacy, Phytoplankton Flambe is perhaps one of the most abundant and
easily accessible dishes that can be ordered in any restaurant around the world.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Paprika
      </spices>
      <source>
      Food Network
      </source>
      <rating>
      Normal
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      A dozen phytoplanton cells
Exactly one pinch of salt
1 green onion
1 gallon of paprika
1 tomato
200 mg of paprika
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Peel and thinly slice the green onion. Toss the phytoplankton and green onion into a bowl and mix.
Now, add a pinch of salt. Next, add 1 gallon of paprika. Then, slowly add the 200 mg of paprika, while mixing.
At this point the paprika should completely overpower the rest of the dish and you should be left with basically
a bowl of paprika. Now throw out the tomato. Mix the paprika thoroughly. Finally, drench it in gasoline and throw
a match on it, and you have Phytoplankton Flambe.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Maple Salmon Recipe
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100764305
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      A very good, and very simple, marinade/sauce for Salmon or any other kind of fish.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Garlic
Garlic Salt
Ground Pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      AllRecipes.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1/4 cup maple syrup
2 tablespoons soy sauce
1 clove garlic, minced
1/4 teaspoon garlic salt
1/8 teaspoon ground black pepper
1 pound salmon
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1.   In a small bowl, mix the maple syrup, soy sauce, garlic, garlic salt, and pepper.
2. Place salmon in a shallow glass baking dish, and coat with the maple syrup mixture. Cover the dish, and marinate salmon in the refrigerator 30 minutes, turning once.
3. Preheat oven to 400 degrees F (200 degrees C).4. Place the baking dish in the preheated oven, and bake salmon uncovered 20 minutes, or until easily flaked with a fork.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Quick Chicken And Wine
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100792933
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Chicken
      </category>
      <description>
      This is a very simple chicken breast recipe excellent for any occasion.
Goes well with white rice or pasta.
Serve with a smile - that's an order!
      </description>
      <spices>
      Black Pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      allrecipes.com (http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Quick-Chicken-And-Wine/Detail.aspx)
      </source>
      <rating>
      High
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      4 skinless, boneless chicken breast halves - cut into strips
2 eggs, beaten
1/2 cup Parmesan cheese
1 pinch salt
1 pinch ground black pepper
1/2 cup white wine
4 tablespoons butter
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1.Season chicken with salt and pepper to taste. In a shallow plate, spread Parmesan cheese. Divide chicken into three parts and dip seasoned chicken in eggs, then coat well with Parmesan cheese. Repeat until all of the chicken pieces are well coated (if you run short on egg and Parmesan, add one more egg and more Parmesan as needed).
2.In a skillet, melt butter or margarine over medium high heat. Cook chicken, stirring frequently, until golden brown.
3.Reduce heat and add wine. Cover and simmer over low heat for 20 minutes
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Perogies
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      unknown
      </contributor>
      <category>
	  Side Dish
      </category>
     <description>
Perogies are a traditional favourite in Eastern European countries,
such as Poland and the Ukraine. It's a household favourite of mine, and many variations
to the filling can be made
     </description>
      <spices>
      pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Perogies/Detail.aspx
      </source>
      <rating>
      mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 cups all-purpose flour
1 teaspoon salt
1 egg, beaten
2/3 cup cold water
1 pound bacon
5 pounds baking potatoes
1 cup shredded Cheddar cheese
salt and pepper to taste
1/4 pound bacon
1 (32 ounce) jar sauerkraut - drained, rinsed and minced
3 tablespoons sour cream
salt and pepper to taste
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      To Make Dough: In a medium bowl combine the flour, salt, egg and water. Mix all together
to form dough; cover bowl and set aside.
To Make Potato Filling: Place potatoes in a large pot. Add water to cover, bring to a boil,
and boil for 25 to 35 minutes or until tender. Remove potatoes from water and mash. Place
bacon in a large, deep skillet. Cook over medium high heat until evenly brown. Drain,
crumble and stir into mashed potatoes. Stir in cheese and season with salt and pepper.
To Make Sauerkraut Filling: Place bacon in a large, deep skillet. Cook over medium high
heat until evenly brown. Drain, crumble and place in a medium bowl. Stir in sauerkraut,
then sour cream. Mix well.
Roll reserved dough out on a floured surface. Cut circles out of dough, using a small
round container. Place a spoonful of potato or sauerkraut filling in the center of each
circle and fold over, pinching edges together to seal. Bring a large pot of lightly
salted water to a boil; drop perogies in boiling water and cook for 4 to 5 minutes, or
until they float.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Bacon Explosion
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100824297
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main Course
      </category>
      <description>
      A tasty man made meal, right from the heart of America. Made with pounds upon pounds of meat,
this delicious meal is best served as a main course for a dinner of epic proportions. Guaranteed
to fill your calorie requirements for the day.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Spicy BBQ Sauce
Spicy BBQ Rub
Spicy Italian Sausage
      </spices>
      <source>
      BBQ Addicts: http://www.bbqaddicts.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      Thick Cut Bacon: 2 Pounds
Spicy Italian Sausage: 2 Pounds
Spicy BBQ Sauce: 1 Jar
Spicy BBQ Rub: 1 Jar
Coriander: 1 Pinch
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Create a 5x5 tight bacon weave, and ensure that it is square shaped.
Lather bacon weave with spicy BBQ rub.
Spread Italian sausage over bacon weave. Press the edges to create a patty shape.
Fry the remaining bacon, chop them up into bite sized pieces, and layer them ontop of the sausage patty.
Lather with spicy BBQ sauce.
Seperate the sausage from the bacon weave at one end, and roll the sausage patty into a large sausage shape.
Roll the bacon weave around the outside of the sausage.
Cook the roll on a barbeque, at a temperature of 225 degrees fahrenheit in a cloud of hickory smoke.
Cooking will take approximately 1 hour for each inch of thickness your roll has.
Lather finished product with spicy BBQ sauce for taste.

Serves 8
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Teriyaki Steak
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100795873
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      An oven baked teriyaki steak sirloin.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Chopped Garlic
Steak Spice
      </spices>
      <source>
      Home Recipe
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 tablespoons steak spice
1 tablespoon chopped garlic
1/2 cup teriyaki marinade
1 steak
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Place the steak in a small container, and fill the
container with the 1/2 cup of teriyaki marinade. Add the
2 tablespoons of steak spice, followed by the 1
tablespoon of chopped garlic to the marinating steak.
Allow the steak to marinate for a couple of hours, or
longer if desired. To cook the steak, heat the oven to
425 degrees Fahrenheit and place the steak on a baking
tray. Once the oven has heated up, place the baking tray
in the oven and cook for 7 minutes to a perfect medium rare.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Zereshk Polo ba Morgh (Barberry Rice with Chicken)
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100836977
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main Course
      </category>
      <description>
      This is a very ancient and hugely popular main dish from Iran.It
can be served in both formal and informal parties.It's a relatively
easy dish to prepare.It is ussually served for lunch but it's
perfectly okay to serve it as dinner too.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Barberry
Turmeric
Black Pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      http://www.persianrecipes.net
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      basmati or long-grain rice, 500 grams
chicken, 800 grams
cooking oil
butter
barberries (dried), four spoons
sugar, one spoon
onions, two large
saffron, 1/2 teaspoon
salt
black pepper
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Remove the skin from chicken pieces.
Marinate chicken in grated onions, salt and pepper for 4-5 hours.
Wash three cups of rice with plain water twice and drain the water.
Pour rice into a non-stick pan.
Add five cups of water, four spoons of oil and two spoons of salt, and mix.
Bring the water to a boil over high temperature. Let the water
boil until water level sinks to just below rice level. Cover the pan,
and cook over low temperature for about half an hour.
Wash barberries twice with cold water and drain the water.
Add sugar and fry in butter over medium heat for about five minutes.
Pour saffron in a small bowl. Pour in 2-3 spoons of hot water and mix.
Fill the bowl with rice and mix well.
Add saffron-rice and barberries to the rest of the rice and mix well.
Cook chicken under grill for 15-20 minutes turning each piece a
few times during cooking.Serve with barberry-rice.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Lamb Tagine
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100237136
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      Morrocan Lamb Dish, best served with Morrocan Couscous or Cucumber Raita.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Paprika
Turmeric
Cumin
Pepper
Cinnamon
Cloves
Cardamom
Salt
Ginger
Saffron
Coriander
      </spices>
      <source>
      (probably from the internet)via sibling
      </source>
      <rating>
      Savoury
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      3 tablespoons olive oil, divided
2 pounds lamb meat, cut into 1 1/2 inch cubes
2 teaspoons paprika
1/4 teaspoon ground turmeric
1/2 teaspoon ground cumin
1/4 teaspoon cayenne pepper
1 teaspoon ground cinnamon
1/4 teaspoon ground cloves
1/2 teaspoon ground cardamom
1 teaspoon kosher salt
1/2 teaspoon ground ginger
1 pinch saffron
3/4 teaspoon garlic powder
3/4 teaspoon ground coriander
2 medium onions, cut into 1-inch cubes
5 carrots, peeled, cut into fourths, then sliced lengthwise into thin strips
3 cloves garlic, minced
1 tablespoon freshly grated ginger
1 lemon, zested
1 (14.5 ounce) can homemade chicken broth or low-sodium canned broth
1 tablespoon sun-dried tomato paste
1 tablespoon honey
1 tablespoon cornstarch (optional)
1 tablespoon water (optional)
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Place diced lamb in a bowl, toss with 2 tablespoons of the olive oil, and set aside.
In a large resealable bag, toss together the paprika, turmeric, cumin, cayenne, cinnamon, cloves, cardamom, salt, ginger, saffron, garlic powder, and coriander; mix well.
Add the lamb to the bag, and toss around to coat well. Refrigerate at least 8 hours, preferably overnight.
Heat 1 tablespoon of olive oil in a large, heavy bottomed pot over medium-high heat.
Add 1/3 of the lamb, and brown well. Remove to a plate, and repeat with remaining lamb.
Add onions and carrots to the pot and cook for 5 minutes. Stir in the fresh garlic and ginger; continue cooking for an additional 5 minutes.
Return the lamb to the pot and stir in the lemon zest, chicken broth, tomato paste, and honey.
Bring to a boil, then reduce heat to low, cover, and simmer for 1 1/2 to 2 hours, stirring occasionally, until the meat is tender.
If the consistency of the tagine is too thin, you may thicken it with a mixture of cornstarch and water during the last 5 minutes.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Hot Cinnamon Quinoa
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100726278
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Breakfast
      </category>
      <description>
      Quinoa (KIN-wah) is a high-protein and gluten-free seed grown in Peru. This dish is a healthy alternative to the already-healthy hot oatmeal breakfast. Quinoa can also be used to substitute for rice.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Cinnamon!
      </spices>
      <source>
      Internet
      </source>
      <rating>
      Easy Peasy
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1/2 cups Quinoa
1 cup water
cinnamon, honey, raisins, etc.
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Bring water to a boil. Add Quinoa and turn heat to minimum. Cover and wait 15 minutes. Quinoa is cooked when the inner core of the seed is transparent. Stir in cinnamon, apples, raisins or honey. Enjoy!
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Orange Romaine Salad Lemon and Pepper Seasoning
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100826217
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Appetizer
      </category>
      <description>
      A unique salad that will intrigue the taste buds. It's lemon flavours mixed with the soft taste of the oranges make a delicious contrast.
      </description>
      <spices>
      McCormic Lemon and Pepper Seasoning
      </spices>
      <source>
      McCormick
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1/4 Cup vegetable oil
1 tbsp lemon juice
1 tbsp mayonaise
1 tsp McCormic Lemon and Pepper Seasoning
1/4 tsp salt
1 head romain lettuce, torn into bite sized peices
1 small red onion, sliced and separated into rings (optional)
1 can (10 oz/284 mL) of mandarin orange segments, drained
1/4 slived almonds, toasted
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      In jar with tight fitting lid, combine oil, lemon juice, mayonnaise, Lemon and Pepper Seasoning and salt.
Shake well until smooth; chill until seving time.
To toast almonds, place on baking sheet. Bake at 350?F(180?C) about 5 minutes.
In large bowl, combine romaine, onion, oranges and almonds.
Toss with dressing just before serving.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Creole Jambalaya
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      Dean Shep
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      A favorite one dish meal of the Old South. Good served with lettuce salad, hot or iced tea and toasted biscuits.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Thyme
      </spices>
      <source>
      www.spicyfoodrecipes.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      6 sliced smoked bacon, diced
1/2 lb. cooked ham
1/2 lb. cooked spicy sausages (Italian, Polish)
1/2 lb. cooked shrimp
1 cup chopped onions
1 can (6 oz) tomato paste
2 green peppers, chopped
4 green onions, sliced
1 tsp. dried thyme leaves
1 tsp. fresh dill OR 1/4 tsp. dried dill leaves
1/2 to 1 tsp. salt
1/2 tsp. black pepper
3 cups cooked rice
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Saute bacon in heavy, deep skillet until crisp. Drain off all but 2 Tbs. of the fat.
Meanwhile, cut ham and sausages into 1/2-inch cubes. Shell and devein shrimp, if necessary. Set aside.
Add onions to bacon. Saute for 2 to 3 minutes or until onions begin to brown.
Stir in tomato paste, green peppers, green onions, ham and sausages. Cook, stirring, for 5 minutes.
Add thyme, dill, salt, black pepper and cooked rice, blending well.
Cover and cook, stirring occasionally, for 20 to 30 minutes longer or until vegetables are tender, adding shrimp the last 5 to 10 minutes.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Maple Salmon Recipe
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100764305
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      A very good, and very simple, marinade/sauce for Salmon or any other kind of fish.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Garlic
Garlic Salt
Ground Pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      AllRecipes.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1/4 cup maple syrup
2 tablespoons soy sauce
1 clove garlic, minced
1/4 teaspoon garlic salt
1/8 teaspoon ground black pepper
1 pound salmon
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1.   In a small bowl, mix the maple syrup, soy sauce, garlic, garlic salt, and pepper.
2. Place salmon in a shallow glass baking dish, and coat with the maple syrup mixture. Cover the dish, and marinate salmon in the refrigerator 30 minutes, turning once.
3. Preheat oven to 400 degrees F (200 degrees C).4. Place the baking dish in the preheated oven, and bake salmon uncovered 20 minutes, or until easily flaked with a fork.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Ranch Burgers
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100726353
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      This is one of the best tasting burger recipes.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Black Pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      allrecipes.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 pounds lean ground beef
1 (1 ounce) package ranch dressing mix
1 egg, lightly beaten
3/4 cup crushed saltine crackers
1 onion, chopped
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Preheat the grill for high heat.
In a bowl, mix the ground beef, ranch dressing mix, egg, crushed crackers, and onion.
Form into hamburger patties.
Lightly oil the grill grate.
Place patties on the grill, and cook 5 minutes per side, or until well done.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Peanut and Carrot Soup
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100841174
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Soup
      </category>
      <description>
      A unique dish that excites the tastebuds. This creamy, orange soup
entices the eyes and the tongue. Normally sweet, it can also be rendered
into a delicious spicy meal by adding red curry paste. An uncommon blend of
root vegetable and the humble legume, peanut, produces an unexpected burst
of flavour.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Cayenne
      </spices>
      <source>
      The Vegetarian Times Complete Cookbook
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      3 tablespoons olive oil
2 cups diced onion
1 pound carrots, peeled and sliced thin
1/2 teaspoon cayenne
2 teaspoons salt
4 cups vegetable stock
1/2 cup peanut butter
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1. Heat the olive oil in a 3-quart saucepan. Saute the onion until soft
and golden. Add the carrots, and saute for 5 minutes. Add the cayenne, salt,
and broth, cover, and cook for 20 minutes, or until the carrots are very
tender. Puree the carrots and onions, and return to the pot.
2. (OPTIONAL) Add 1 tablespoon of red curry paste for a spicier dish.
3. Add peanut butter, and whisk well. Cook for 5 minutes. Adjust the
seasoning to taste. Ladle into 6 bowls.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Chocolate Chip Peppermint Cookies
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100822684
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dessert
      </category>
      <description>
      These appetizing treats are a festive version of the classic and delicious chocolate chip cookie.
      </description>
      <spices>
      
      </spices>
      <source>
      I got the recipe for these cookies from an old cookbook of my mothers. I can't remember the exact name of the book.
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild, these treats are sweet, not spicy.
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2/3 cup butter
2/3 cup shortening
1 cup white sugar
1 cup brown sugar
2 large eggs
2 teaspoons peppermint extract
1 teaspoon salt
1 teaspoon baking soda
1 cup crushed peppermint candies
1 1/2 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips
3 cups flour
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Preheat your oven to 375C. Mix together the butter, shortening, white sugar, and brown sugar. Mix well. Add in the eggs and peppermint extract. Mix well. Add in the baking soda, salt, flour, chocolate chips, and peppermint candies. Mix well. Drop onto lightly greased cookie sheets by tsps, keeping 2 apart. Bake for 8-10 minutes.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Homemade Pierogies with Sour Cream
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100789944
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main course
      </category>
      <description>
      This is my Grandma's homemade recipe.  Since I am half Polish, pierogies are highly favoured in our family.  They are always made on special occasions and holidays, such as Thanksgiving and Christmas.  Sour cream in the dough is the secret to a great tasting pierogie!!
      </description>
      <spices>
      N/A
      </spices>
      <source>
      Grandma's Homemade Pierogies
      </source>
      <rating>
      High
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 cups flour, plus extra for kneading and rolling dough
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 large egg
1/2 cup sour cream, plus extra to serve with the pierogi
1/4 cup butter, softened and cut into small pieces
butter and onions for sauteing
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      To prepare the pierogi dough, mix together the flour and salt. Beat the egg, then add all at once to the flour mixture. Add the 1/2 cup sour cream and the softened butter pieces and work until the dough loses most of its stickiness (about 5-7 minutes). You can use a food processor with a dough hook for this, but be careful not to overbeat. Wrap the dough in plastic and refrigerate for 20-30 minutes or overnight; the dough can be kept in the refrigerator for up to 2 days. Each batch of dough makes about 12-15 pierogies, depending on size. Roll the pierogi dough on a floured board or countertop until 1/8" thick. Cut circles of dough (2" for small pierogies and 3-3 1/2" for large pierogies) with a cookie cutter or drinking glass. Place a small ball of filling (about a tablespoon) on each dough round and fold the dough over, forming a semi-circle. Press the edges together with the tines of a fork. Boil the perogies a few at a time in a large pot of water. They are done when they float to the top (about 8-10 minutes). Rinse in cool water and let dry. Saute chopped onions in butter in a large pan until onions are soft. Then add pierogies and pan fry until lightly crispy. Serve with a side of sour cream for a true Pittsburgh pierogi meal.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Power Granola
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100670676
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Breakfast
      </category>
      <description>
      Power-start your day with this rolled oat and bran cereal with flaxseed. Unleash your inner healthly cook.
      </description>
      <spices>
      ground cinnanmon
      </spices>
      <source>
      I got this recipe from a co-worker who got it from a cook book for diabitics.
Unfortantly she only had a copy of it that didn't have the recipe_name of the book on it.
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 cups large-flake rolled oats
1/2 cup natural bran
1/3 cup ground flaxseed
1/3 granular low-calorie sweetener with surcralose
1/4 cup sliced almonds
2 tsp ground cinnanmon
1/3 cup orange juice
2 tbsp liquid honey
2 tsp vanilla extract
1/3 cup dried cranberries, halved
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      In a medium bowl, combine rolled oats, bran, flaxseed,sweetner, oat bran, almonds and cinnamon.
In a glass measure, combine orange juice honey, oil and vanilla.
Pour over rolled oat mixture stir well.
Spray a baking pan with non-stick cooking spray.
Spread the oat mixture in a thin layer on the pan.
Bake in 300F or 150C oven for 10 minutes; stir well.
Bake an additional 8 minutes or until golden brown.
Remove from oven; cool. Stir in cranberries and \nstore in a tightly sealed container.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Super Tofu Boy
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100836987
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main Course
      </category>
      <description>
      Let's consider this a rough outline because I never cook it the same way. It's probably similar to many other recipes of stri-fried tofu. It's nice because it'll be ready in less than twenty minutes, there's a wide range of flavors, and lots of room to experiment with spices and other vegetables. This should be enough for a one person dinner.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Black pepper
Garlic
      </spices>
      <source>
      I designed this dish when I became vegetarian (I don't like to follow recipes)
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      100g of tofu
Olive or canola oil for the pan
A few leaves of kale
A medium sized stalk (and head) of brocoli
One medium zucchini
Some cauliflower
A medium onion
As much garlic as you like
Enough Tamari sauce
Black pepper to taste
A few raw almonds can be nice
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Pour some olive oil in a pan.
Cut the tofu in small cubes.
Add cubes to the pan, heat the pan at a level just below medium.
Add Tamari sauce so that every cube of tofu can soak up some of it.
Move the cubes around so that each side can get lightly fried.
Once the tofu shows a light yellow-brown coat, add cut cauliflower and brocoli.
Add zucchini, sliced the way you like to slice that kind of stuff.
Add onion, cut however you like.
Add raw almonds if you think it'll taste good.
Add kale and ground fresh garlic toward the end, which is when you the cauliflower is softened up just enough.
Kale cooks fast, so during the last couple of minutes you can add ground black pepper and any other spice you like.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Peanut and Carrot Soup
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100841174
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Soup
      </category>
      <description>
      A unique dish that excites the tastebuds. This creamy, orange soup entices the eyes and the tongue. Normally sweet, it can also be rendered into a delicious spicy meal by adding red curry paste. An uncommon blend of root vegetable and the humble legume, peanut, produces an unexpected burst of flavour.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Cayenne
      </spices>
      <source>
      The Vegetarian Times Complete Cookbook
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      3 tablespoons olive oil
2 cups diced onion
1 pound carrots, peeled and sliced thin
1/2 teaspoon cayenne
2 teaspoons salt
4 cups vegetable stock
1/2 cup peanut butter
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1. Heat the olive oil in a 3-quart saucepan. Saute the onion until soft and golden. Add the carrots, and saute for 5 minutes. Add the cayenne, salt, and broth, cover, and cook for 20 minutes, or until the carrots are very tender. Puree the carrots and onions, and return to the pot.
2. (OPTIONAL) Add 1 tablespoon of red curry paste for a spicier dish.
3. Add peanut butter, and whisk well. Cook for 5 minutes. Adjust the seasoning to taste. Ladle into 6 bowls.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Cola Chicken Wings
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100673482
      </contributor>
      <category>
      main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      This is a great chinese food. It is sweet and a little spicy. Children like it so much.
Leftovers store well refrigerated for several days.
      </description>
      <spices>
      chili powder
ground cumin
      </spices>
      <source>
      Home made
      </source>
      <rating>
      Hot
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      6 to 8 chicken wings
1 cup cola
3 tablespoons olive oil
1/2 teaspoon ground cumin
1 green onions, chopped
some garlic, chopped
2 tablespoon chili powder
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Put some water in a pan, until the water boiling, put the wings in the pan, cook until seven rare.
Take the wings out off water, wash the pan and clean the water.
Put olive oil in the pan, until it warm put some green onion and garlic in, then,put all the wings, ground cumin and chili power in.
When there have some scent,put cola in keep cooking about 7 to 10mins. (don't put any water in) until the skin of wings become yellow.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Pineapple Squares
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100831146
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dessert
      </category>
      <description>
      Delicious gooey pineapple dessert squares with a cookie layer,
followed by pineapple and a succulent meringue topping.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Vanilla
      </spices>
      <source>
      Grandmother
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      400 mL brown sugar
125 mL butter
2 eggs
375 mL flour
5 mL baking powder
5 mL vanilla
400 mL crushed pineapple, drained
125 mL nuts
125 coconut
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Whip together 325 mL of brown sugar, 125 mL of butter, and the yolks of both eggs.
Make sure to save the egg whites for later.  After this combination has been made into
a cream, blend in 375 mL of flour, 5 mL baking powder, and 5 mL vanilla.  Bake this in a
9 inch by 9 inch pan at 350 degrees for 10 minutes.  Once it's finished, cover it with
the crushed pineapple.  Beat the two egg whites until they are stiff, then fold in the
last 75 mL of brown sugar, 125 mL of nuts, and 125 mL of coconut.  Spread this on top of
the pineapple and bake the whole thing at 350 degrees for 20 to 30 minutes.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Mild Shrimp Curry
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100798679
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main Dish
      </category>
      <description>
      A modern style, Southwest Asian dish; recommended for those who likes spicy
food. Preparation may be long, but definitely worth the time. Shrimp is
also a great source of energy for the human body; it contains a high
percentage of protein.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Parsley
Turmeric
Coriander
Cumin Seeds
Fennel Seed
      </spices>
      <source>
      Taste Book Recipes
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 pounds shrimp
1 ancho chile
1 large onion
3 tablespoons vegetable oil
1 clove garlic, minced
1 stalk celery, chopped
1 tablespoon chopped parsley
1/2 teaspoon turmeric
1 teaspoon ground coriander
1 teaspoon ground fennel seed
1 teaspoon ground cumin seed
1/2 cup yogurt
2 tablespoons fresh coriander, chopped
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1. Peel the shrimp, reserving the shells, and sprinkle them with salt.
Rinse thoroughly, drain and repeat the process two more times. Blot dry
with paper towels.
2. Tear the ancho chile in strips, discarding the seeds, and soak for 20 to
30 minutes in 1 cup hot water.
3. Place the shrimp shells in a large saucepan with half the onion,
coarsely chopped, the celery and parsley. Add 5 cups water and bring to
boil. Simmer for 30 minutes.
4. Chop the remaining half-onion and sautee in the vegetable oil until
golden brown, stirring frequently. Add the garlic and cook for one minute,
then add the spices. Stir-fry for a minute, then add 1 cup of the shrimp
stock. Boil rapidly for 5 minutes. Meanwhile, puree the ancho chile in its
soaking liquid until smooth. Add to the sauce, along with the rest of the
shrimp stock. Cook for 20 minutes.
5. Add the shrimp and cook for about 3 minutes. Add the yogurt and heat
through. Sprinkle with coriander and serve on basmati rice.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Pad Thai
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100684954
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      A Westernized version of Southeast Asian dish.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Chili Flakes
      </spices>
      <source>
      Internet
      </source>
      <rating>
      High
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      Tofu or Chicken
Rice Noodles
2 cloves of garlic
1 onion
1 green pepper
1/2 cup green peas
3 tbsp peanut butter
1/3 cup sugar
1/4 cup soy sauce
1/4 cup lemon juice extract
1/2 tsp chili flakes
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Cook rice noodles according to package directions. Fry chicken or tofu with garlic initially then add additional vegetables. Thoroughly mix the peanut butter, soy sauce, lemon juice extract, sugar, and chili flakes in a bowl. When veggies and rice noodles are ready, mix all components into main frying apparatus. Stir until liquid has simmered off. Serve!
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Pasta Alfredo
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100811212
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dinner Meal
      </category>
      <description>
      This Alfredo Pasta recipe is rich and tasty. Not only is the recipe fail-safe, but it can be made quickly and easily even by students living away from home who have never cooked before. The recipe is vary simmlair to the Alfredo Pasta served at Olive Gardens, It taste the same and is cheaper.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Pepper and Garlic
      </spices>
      <source>
      Wilbour, Todd (1997), Top Secret Restaurant Recipes, New York, New York, The Penguin Group
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1/2 Cup of Butter, 1 12 Ounce box of Fettuccine Pasta, 2 Cups of heavy Cream, 1/8 teaspon of Garlic, 1/8 teaspon of Pepper, 1/8 cup grated Parmesan Cheese
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1)Melt the Butter in a Medium Saucepan over medium heat, 2) Add the cream, garlic, and pepper and simmer for 10-12 min or until thick, 3) At the same time, bring 4-6 quarts of water to a boil and add the pasta, 4) When the Alfredo sauce has reached your desired consistency, stir in parmesan cheese, 5) When the pasta is cooked, drain it and serve with Alfredo Sauce
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Mrs. Fields Chocolate Chip Cookies
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      #100789120
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dessert
      </category>
      <description>
      These may or may not be the ultimate in chocolate chip cookies.  I'll give you a hint: they are.  For a little something to make their eyes go wide, consider adding a teaspoon of almond extract!
      </description>
      <spices>
      Vanilla
      </spices>
      <source>
      Mrs. Fields
      </source>
      <rating>
      Not spicy in the least.
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 cup soft butter
?? cup sugar
1?? cup brown sugar
2 eggs
2?? tsp vanilla extract
2?? cups all purpose flour
?? tsp salt
1 tsp baking powder
1 tsp baking soda
1 (12 oz bag) semi-sweet chocolate chip
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Cream butter and sugars together and then beat eggs and vanilla in.
Sift together dry ingredients and add to creamed mixture; stir well.
Fold chocolate chips and put golfball sized balls on an un-greased pan.
Bake @ 350??F for 7-9 min.  (450??2 K for 480??80 s)  If cookies are not golden brown, continue baking for 2 min.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Penultimate Pancakes
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100765617
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Breakfast
      </category>
      <description>
      null
      </description>
      <spices>
      
      </spices>
      <source>
      http://www.canadianfreestuff.com/forum/f55/homemade-pancake-recipe-scratch-23707/
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 1/2 cups flour
2 1/2 tsp baking powder
1 tsp salt
1 beaten egg
1 1/2 cup milk
1 tsp vanilla (real, not artificial)
1 tsp oil per pancake
Real Maple Syrup
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Heat a large frying pan to medium high heat. Water
droplets should sizzle and disappear almost quickly. Mix
together the baking powder, flour and salt in a large bowl.
Then add the beaten egg, milk, and vanilla. Mix until most
lumps disappear (do not overmix). Cook in the pan with 1
tsp of oil per pancake. When bubbles appear on the top of
the pancake, it is time to flip it. Serve with butter and
yummy maple syrup.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Polish Cabbage Rolls
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100822697
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main course
      </category>
      <description>
      Stuffed Cabbage Rolls are the epitome of comfort food.
Pork and beef mixed with rice or barley are nestled in a cabbage leaf
and cooked in the oven or on the stove until tender.
It is traditional Polish food and are called golabki
which literally means "little pigeons." Usually, the sauce is
what sets them apart.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Black pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      Polish recipe
      </source>
      <rating>
      Midly spice
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 whole head cabbage, about 4 pounds
1 large onion, chopped
2 tablespoons butter
1 pound ground beef
1/2 pound ground pork
1 1/2 cups cooked rice
1 teaspoon finely chopped garlic
1 teaspoon salt
1/4 teaspoon black pepper
1 cup beef stock
Sour cream for garnish (optional)
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Heat oven to 350 degrees.
Remove core from cabbage. Place whole head in a large pot filled with boiling, salted water. Cover and cook 3 minutes, or until softened enough to pull off individual leaves. You will need about 18 leaves.
When leaves are cool enough to handle, use a paring knife to cut away the thick center stem from each leaf, without cutting all the way through.
Chop the remaining cabbage and place it in the bottom of a casserole dish or Dutch oven.
Saute the chopped onion in butter in a large frying pan until tender, and let it cool.
Mix cooled onions with beef, pork, rice, garlic, salt and black pepper until well combined. Don't overmix or the meat will become tough.
Place about 1/2 cup of meat on each cabbage leaf. Roll away from you to encase the meat. Flip the right side of the leaf to the middle, then flip the left side. You will have something that looks like an envelope. Once again, roll away from you to create a neat little roll.
Place the cabbage rolls on top of the chopped cabbage in the casserole dish or Dutch oven, seasoning each layer with salt and pepper. Pour beef stock over rolls, cover and place in oven. Bake for 1 hour or until cabbage is tender and meat is cooked.
Serve with pan juices and a drizzle of sour cream, or mix the pan juices with sour cream and ladle it over the cabbage rolls.
Cabbage rolls freeze well before or after cooking, and can be made in a slow cooker (see your manufacturer's instructions).
Note: Since they can be eaten hot or at room temperature, mini cabbage rolls make great appetizers. Just spear them with a frilled toothpick and you're good to go!
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Matar Paneer
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100795499
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      A curry of peas, tomatoes and paneer cheese.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Cinnamon
Ginger
Garlic
      </spices>
      <source>
      DailyDinner
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      Cheese Paneer 200 ml
Oil Vegetable 15 ml
Onion 2 sm
Garlic 2 cloves
Ginger 15 ml
Cinnamon 1 ml
Cardamon - ground 1 ml
Cayenne Pepper 1 ml
Cloves - Ground 1 dash
Tomatoes - whole canned 1 sm can
Peas - Frozen 200 ml
Honey 2 ml
Cilantro 45 ml
Rice - White 200 ml
Water 400 ml
Salt 5 ml
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Put water for rice on to boil, when boiling add the rice, cover and set the heat to low.
In a bowl mix the cinnamon, cardamom, cayenne and cloves.
Peel slice and chop the onion and ginger. Put the garlic in a press.
Measure the peas.
In a fry pan on a medium burner put oil and the onions. Cook until translucent.
Turn the heat to medium low. Add the garlic, then spices and cook a minute
Drain the inner liquid from the tomatoes and crush into the pan. Let cook 10 minutes. Add tomato liquid as necessary.
Add the peas and paneer and cook another 10 minutes.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      BIGOS
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100679274
      </contributor>
      <category>
      main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      This is the most traditional Polish dish. It is also known as "Hunter's stew".
There is no one, unique recipe for this dish and it varies depending on the region and family traditions.
Typical ingredients are sauerkraut, white cabbage, various cuts of meat and sausages.
It is mostly eaten with bread. The interesting fact about Bigos is that the longer it is kept in a cool
place, its flavour intensifies and taste is even better. It is often served during Christmas.
      </description>
      <spices>
      salt
pepper
bay leaves
      </spices>
      <source>
      This is a family recipe given to me by my Mother.
      </source>
      <rating>
      medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2kg of sauerkraut
3g of dry wild mushrooms
1 large onion
200g of beef
200g of pork
200g of veal
500g of sausage, ham and smoked bacon
2 bay leaves
salt
ground pepper
pepper corn
1 beef bouillon
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Chop sauerkraut, place it in a large pot and cover with water. Add mushrooms, bouillon cube, bay leaves,
about 15 pepper corns and some ground pepper. Cook on low heat for about 3 hours.
Slice an onion and add it to the sauerkraut. Cut sausage, ham and bacon into small 1x1x1cm cubes
and add them to the pot with sauerkraut.
In a large pan heat enough oil to cover the bottom, once the oil is heated place all three meats on pan.
Sear the meat until brown on both sides. Take the meat off the pan and cut it in a small cubes and add it to the
pot with the sauerkraut. Mix the bigos once in a while and cook for about 3 hours until all the meat and
mushrooms are soft. Add salt and more ground pepper to taste.
To intensify the flavour you may add 1/2 a bottle of dry red wine at the end of the cooking.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Lentil Curry
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100707603
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Side dish
      </category>
      <description>
      Found it from a book. It has the taste of lentil with salt and spice.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Bit of hot curry powder
      </spices>
      <source>
      Book - indian style
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 garlic cloves, chopped.
1/2 onion, chopped
1/4 cup milk
1 spoon of hot curry powder
2 teaspoon salt
4 cup of water
2 cup of washed lentil
3 spoon of olive oil
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      In a medium pot, add the lentil and water together and cook it for
about 15min at medium heat.
In the mean time, fry the onion and garlic in a frying pan using the olive oil.
Add the fried onion and garlic to the lentil pot with rest of the ingredient mentioned about.
Let it cook for another 15 or until the lentil is mashable.  Now ready to serve.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Banana Muffins.
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100679857
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dessert
      </category>
      <description>
      Yummy Muffins!
      </description>
      <spices>
      None
      </spices>
      <source>
      Mom's Recepie.
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1) 1/2 cup (or 1 stick) butter or margarine, softened
2) 1 cup sugar
3) 2 large eggs
4) 2 large ripe bananas, mashed
5) 2 cups flour (all-purpose)
6) 1 teaspoon salt
7) 1 teaspoon baking powder
8) 1 cup buttermilk
9) 1/2 cup chopped walnuts
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1) Preheat oven to 400??.
2) Beat together butter and sugar at medium\n speed of mixer or by hand, until light and fluffy. Add eggs, 1 at a time, beating well each time. Add bananas and beat until smooth.
3) In a separate bowl, mix together flour, salt, baking powder and baking soda.
4) Alternate stirring in part of the flour mixture and part of the buttermilk  into the egg mixture until all is added and mixture is just moistened.
5) Do not overmix. Batter will not look completely smooth.
6) Stir in nuts and vanilla.
7) Grease 12 standard size muffin tins or use paper cupcake cups.
8) Spoon batter into muffin cups, filling 2/3 full.Bake 15-18 minutes until lightly golden. Cool muffin pan slightly before turning out the muffins. Cool muffins on a rack a bit more.
9) Makes 12 medium size muffins. Great served warm with butter
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Light Tiramisu
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100823842
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dessert
      </category>
      <description>
      An Italian dessert cake made of biscuits dipped in coffee, layered with cream.
Simple, easy to make, and very delicious, tiramisu is a light dessert capable of brightening anyone's day.
      </description>
      <spices>
      cocoa powder
      </spices>
      <source>
      http://www.foodnetwork.ca/recipes/desserts/recipe.html?dishID=8243
      </source>
      <rating>
      N/A
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      3/2 cup hot strong coffee

1/4 cup sugar

475 grams ricotta cheese

1/2 cup light cream cheese

2 tablespoons cocoa liquer

3 egg whites

13 ladyfingers

1 tablespoon cocoa powder
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1. Dissolve 2 tablespoons of sugar in the coffee, refrigerate.
2. Process the ricotta, liquer, and cream cheese until smooth, set aside.
3. Beat egg whites in a large bowl.
4. Add sugar while continuing beating the egg whites.
5. Fold the cheese mixture from step 2 into the egg whites.
6. Soak the ladyfingers in the coffee.
7. Line the bottom of a 12-cup glass serving bowl with ladyfingers.

8. Cover the lady fingers with half of the cheese mixture.
9. Lay the remaining ladyfingers on the cheese mixture.
10. Layer the remaining cheese mixture on top.
11. Dust the top with cocoa powder.
12. Chill for 2 hours.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Spaghetti With Peanut Butter Sauce
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100836211
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      Spicy peanut spaghetti with a better than expected taste.
      </description>
      <spices>
      crushed garlic
chili sauce
cilantro
      </spices>
      <source>
      All Recipes
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1/2 cup creamy peanut butter
1/3 cup hot water
1 tablespoon light soy sauce
1 clove crushed garlic
1/3 cup heavy whipping cream
1 teaspoon sesame oil
1 dash chili sauce
12 ounces spaghetti
3 teaspoons chopped fresh cilantro
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1.	Place the peanut butter in a small glass, and add the hot water; stir with a fork until smooth. Mix in soy sauce, garlic, cream, sesame oil, chili sauce until smooth. Set aside.
2.	Cook pasta in a large pot of boiling water until done. Drain well.
3.	Place the drained pasta in a bowl. Stir the reserved peanut butter mixture together again; add to the cooked pasta. Toss all together, and garnish with cilantro
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Plum Chutney
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100826784
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Side Dish
      </category>
      <description>
      Traditional Australian dish, served well with red meat. Serves 1 cup of chutney
      </description>
      <spices>
      Rosemary
      </spices>
      <source>
      Margaret E. Walker; www.ragemech.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1/2 cup cranberry sauce
1/2 cup plums chopped (drain if canned)
1/3 cup balsamic vinegar
2 tablespoons brown sugar
1 tablespoon fresh rosemary, chopped
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      combine all ingredients in a saucepan and bring slowly to a boil, stir until the sugar is dissolved. Reduce to a simmer and cook, uncovered, for 20 minutes or until the mixture thickens.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Cajun Jambalaya
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100812529
      </contributor>
      <category>
      null
      </category>
      <description>
      Traditional Jambalaya without the heat!
      </description>
      <spices>
      null
      </spices>
      <source>
      North U.S.A
      </source>
      <rating>
      Everyone will Enjoy
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 teaspoons olive oil
2 boneless skinless chicken breasts, cut into bite-size pieces
8 ounces kielbasa, diced
1 onion, diced
1 green bell pepper, diced
1/2 cup diced celery
2 tablespoons chopped garlic
1/4 teaspoon cayenne pepper
1/2 teaspoon onion powder
salt and ground black pepper to taste
2 cups uncooked white rice
4 cups chicken stock
3 bay leaves
2 teaspoons Worcestershire sauce
1 teaspoon hot pepper sauce
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Heat oil in a large pot over medium high heat. Saute chicken and kielbasa until lightly
browned, about 5 minutes. Stir in onion, bell pepper, celery and garlic. Season with
cayenne, onion powder, salt and pepper. Cook 5 minutes, or until onion is tender and
translucent. Add rice, then stir in chicken stock and bay leaves. Bring to a boil, then
reduce heat, cover, and simmer 20 minutes, or until rice is tender. Stir in the
Worcestershire sauce and hot pepper sauce
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Bloody Ceasar
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100710713
      </contributor>
      <category>
      appetizer
      </category>
      <description>
      Delicious with breakfast, lunch, dinner or anytime of the day, the Bloody ceasar is a great way to increase your vegetable intake while enjoying a casual drink. Ranging from mild to super spicey, the ceaser can be made to suit anyone's taste.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Worcestershire sauce
celery salt
Tabasco sauce
      </spices>
      <source>
      http://gocanada.about.com/od/recipesfromcanada/r/caesar_recipe.htm
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild, Medium, or Hot, the bloody ceaser recipe can be made to taste.
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      clamato juice, regular or spicey
worchestershire sauce
tabasco sauce
celery  salt
garnish of celery stalk or bean
ice
1 or 2 ounces of vodka
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Rim a pint glass with celery salt
Fill the glass with ice
Pour Worcestershire sauce into glass to the count of three (three good, solid shakes)
Add Tabasco to taste: for heat-lovers, 7-10 drops.
Add 1-2 ounces of vodka (or no vodka for virgin Caesar)
Top with Clamato juice
Garnish with celery stalk or bean
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Grill Master Chicken Wings
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100688723
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Appetizer
      </category>
      <description>
      These tasty chicken wings make a great appetizer. This recipe requires
few ingredients and can be made in only 30 minutes!
      </description>
      <spices>
      1/4 cup hot pepper sauce
      </spices>
      <source>
      allrecipes.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1/2 cup soy sauce
1/2 cup Italian salad dressing
3 pounds chicken wings, cut apart at joints, wing tips discarded
1/4 cup butter
1 teaspoon soy sauce
1/4 cup hot pepper sauce
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      1. Combine 1/2 cup soy sauce, Italian dressing, and chicken wings in
a large, zip-top bag. Close bag and refrigerate 4 hours to overnight.
2. Preheat an outdoor grill for medium heat. In a small saucepan, melt
the butter. Stir in the 1 teaspoon soy sauce and the hot pepper sauce. Turn
off heat and reserve.
3. Remove the chicken wings from the marinade and pat dry. Cook the wings
on the preheated grill, turning occasionally, until the chicken is well browned
and no longer pink, 25 to 30 minutes.
4. Place grilled wings in a large bowl. Pour butter sauce over wings;
toss to mix well.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Indian Curry
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      null
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main Course
      </category>
      <description>
      An indian curry with thick gravy that emanates an coconut flavor.
It originates from southern India and therefore is hotter than traditional
curries.
      </description>
      <spices>
      turmeric powder
      </spices>
      <source>
      www.curryfood-recipe.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      hot
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 chicken of 1.5kg
2 tablespoons ghee
1 stalk lemon grass
1 cinnamon stick
10 sprigs curry leaves
500ml chicken stock
125ml plain yogurt
10 red chilies
20g shallots
20g garlic
30g ginger
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Rinse chicken and cut into pieces. Cut lemon grass into sections and crush.
To make Paste: Place Ingredients B into a food processor and blend until a fine
paste is formed. Remove and set aside.
Heat wok with ghee, fry lemon grass until fragrant. Add cinnamon stick and chicken.
Stir-fry briefly. Add ground paste and stir-fry until fragrant.
Add Seasonings and curry leaves. Stir-fry evenly. Pour in chicken stock and
bring to a boil using medium heat. Switch to low heat and simmer for 15 minutes.
Lastly, pour in yogurt. Mix well and cook briefly. Serve.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Frozen Chocolate-Covered Bananas
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100831601
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dessert
      </category>
      <description>
      An easy and tasty frozen dessert. This dessert is not only simple enough
for children to make, but will also satisfy that sweet craving. With 100
calories and the benefits of a ripe banana, you can feed your sweet tooth while
watching your waist line.
      </description>
      <spices>
      
      </spices>
      <source>
      Eating Well Magazine
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      4 large ripe bananas, peeled and cut into thirds crosswise
3/4 cup semisweet or bittersweet chocolate chips, melted
1/4 cup shredded coconut
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Peel 4 large bananas, cut into thirds and insert a popsicle stick into
the cut end of each piece.
Melt 3/4 cup semisweet or bittersweet chocolate chips.
Cover each banana with melted chocolate and sprinkle with coconut.
Place the bananas on a baking sheet lined with parchment or wax paper and freeze
until frozen, about 2 hours.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Chocolate Chips Oatmeal Squares
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      1006387999
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Desert
      </category>
      <description>
      This is an Egg Free Oatmeal cookie that is made in squares rather than cookie shape.\n The Square pan helps keep the cookies moist and flavourfull.
      </description>
      <spices>
      
      </spices>
      <source>
      Grandma
      </source>
      <rating>
      5
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1c. butter softened
1/4c. sugar
3/4c. packed brown sugar
1tsp. vanilla
1/2c. boiling water
1tsp. baking soda
2c. oatmeal
1 1/2c. flour
1c. chocolate chips
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Cream butter and sugar and brown sugar, vanilla.  Mix the flour and oatmeal together in a bowl. In a 1 cup measure  place the boiling and add the baking soda then pour that into the butter and sugar, mix then add the oatmeal and flour. Stir in the chocolate chips and spread into a foil lined pan and bake.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Spicy Italian Sausage Meatballs Recipe
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100739213
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main Dish
      </category>
      <description>
      The obvious way to serve these spicy meatballs is over spaghetti, linguini or fettuccine. However, they are also good served with pepper and eggs with crusty bread at brunch. Spoon some of the sauce over the pepper and eggs. Just delicious.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Poultry seasoning
      </spices>
      <source>
      Family Recipe
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 Lb. Italian hot sausage (with or without casing)
1/2 Tspn poultry seasoning
1 Small onion, diced
1 Egg, beaten
1/2 Cup bread crumbs
3/4 Cup chili sauce
1/2 Cup ketchup
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      -If you have purchased sausage in a casing, slide a knife down the casing to break it open, and then remove the sausage. Place sausage, diced onion, egg and poultry seasoning and bread crumbs in a large bowl and mix ingredients well. Do not over mix.
-Make 8 to 10 meatballs and brown them evenly in a large frying pan over medium high heat. When meatballs have browned, remove grease by pouring it from pan. Remove pan from heat while you mix the chili sauce and ketchup together. Pour sauce mix over meatballs.
-Stir meatballs and sauce gently to blend well, making sure all meatballs have sauce. Cover frying pan and continue cooking over medium low heat for 25 to 30 minutes until the meatballs are done. Serve over pasta.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Dry Coconut Chicken
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100802343
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main Course
      </category>
      <description>
      This is a famous South Asian dish. people are having this dish occasionally.It can be served with rice or bread. The challangable part of this dish is the dry grinding coconut. The coconut need to be very coarse and dry (as dry as possible).
      </description>
      <spices>
      Fennel seed
Black Peppercorns
Cumin
Fenugreek seeds
Red Chilli
Poppy seeds
Garlic flakes
Tarmarind
Curry Leaves
      </spices>
      <source>
      Family Recipe
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      8  medium sized pieces (about 800  grams) of chicken
2  tablespoon(s) coriander seeds
?  teaspoon(s) each of fennel seeds (saunf)and turmeric powder
1  teaspoon(s) each of black peppercorns, cumin and fenugreek seeds
1  tablespoon(s) poppy seeds
12  garlic flakes
12  whole dry red chillies roasted
1  tablespoon(s) tamarind paste
1  medium sized coconut grated
8  curry leaves
1  large onion(s) finely chopped
2  tablespoons clarified butter/ butter/ oil
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Heat a little clarified butter (ghee) / butter in a pan and roast the black peppercorns, turmeric powder, fennel, coriander and poppy seeds till aromatic. Allow to cool. Dry grind along with roasted red chillies and tamarind paste. This is the first paste.
Coarsely grind the grated coconut, garlic and cumin seeds (for just a round or two) without adding any water at all, till a ball can be formed of the paste. This is the second paste.
1. Mix the chicken with the first paste. Cover and cook (without adding water) on low level in a heavy-bottomed pan for about 25  minute(s) or till the chicken is almost cooked.
2. Add the second paste and salt to taste. Cover and cook on low level for about 3  minutes or till the chicken is fully cooked.
3. Heat the clarified butter (ghee) / butter in a pan, drop in the curry leaves and fry for a few seconds. Add the finely chopped onions and fry till brown. pour this garnish over the chicken.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Garlic Lemon Chicken
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100716355
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      The combination of easy preparation and great taste makes this
delicious lemony chicken a great choice for family dinner night. Meant
to serve 8 (unless they are teenagers, then it will feed 6).
      </description>
      <spices>
      Lemon
Garlic
Oregano
Salt
Pepper
Parsley
      </spices>
      <source>
      Canadian Living
      </source>
      <rating>
      High
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      12 chicken pieces
1 tbsp vegetable oil
1 lemon, cut into wedges
1/4 cup lemon juice
20 cloves of garlic, peeled
2 tbsp chopped fresh oregano
1/2 eash, salt and pepper
1 tbsp chopped fresh parsley
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Cut any large chicken pieces in half. In large nonstick skillet, heat oil over medium-high heat; brown chicken, in batches, about 5 minutes. Drain off fat.

Arrange chicken and lemon wedges in 13- x 9-inch (3 L) glass baking dish. Sprinkle with lemon juice, garlic, oregano, salt and pepper.

Bake in 425?F (220?C) oven, turning and basting twice, until breasts are no longer pink inside and juices run clear when thighs are pierced, about 30 minutes. (Make-ahead: Let cool for 30 minutes. Refrigerate until cold. Cover with foil and refrigerate for up to 1 day. Reheat, covered, in 375?F/190?C oven, basting once, for 15 minutes.) Sprinkle with parsley.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Durango Beer Chili
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100745020
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main Course
      </category>
      <description>
      Hot and spicy chili made with your favourite dark beer or ale!Perfect for cold winter days especially after skiing or a skate on the canal!
      </description>
      <spices>
      Chili Powder
Bay Leaves
Salt
Cumin
Black Pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      Cooking with beer
      </source>
      <rating>
      Hot
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 lbs lean ground beef
1 lbs boneless sirloin steak cut into small cubes
2 medium chopped onions
1 Green Bell Pepper seeded and chopped
4 minced garlic cloves
1/4 cup of tomato paste
2 chopped Jalapeno peppers seeds in for more spice
2 Bay Leaves
5 tablespoons of chili powder
1 teaspoon of salt
1 teaspoon ground cumin
1 teaspoon of ground black pepper
2 cans whole tomatoes (drained)
1 bottle of favourite dark lager or bock beer
1 can of beef broth
2 cans of drained kidney beans
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Start by cooking the ground beef in a pan. Once cooked add to a large mixing bowl. Add the chopped up steak and the rest of the ingredients and mix.
Place the mix inside a slow cooker and turn on low. Cook for 6-8 hours and serve with grated cheese and chives if desired.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Creole Jambalaya
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100829563
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      A favorite one dish meal of the Old South. Good served with lettuce salad, hot or iced tea and toasted biscuits.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Thyme
      </spices>
      <source>
      www.spicyfoodrecipes.com
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      6 sliced smoked bacon, diced
1/2 lb. cooked ham
1/2 lb. cooked spicy sausages (Italian, Polish)
1/2 lb. cooked shrimp
1 cup chopped onions
1 can (6 oz) tomato paste
2 green peppers, chopped
4 green onions, sliced
1 tsp. dried thyme leaves
1 tsp. fresh dill OR 1/4 tsp. dried dill leaves
1/2 to 1 tsp. salt
1/2 tsp. black pepper
3 cups cooked rice
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Saute bacon in heavy, deep skillet until crisp. Drain off all but 2 Tbs. of the fat.
Meanwhile, cut ham and sausages into 1/2-inch cubes. Shell and devein shrimp, if necessary. Set aside.
Add onions to bacon. Saute for 2 to 3 minutes or until onions begin to brown.
Stir in tomato paste, green peppers, green onions, ham and sausages. Cook, stirring, for 5 minutes.
Add thyme, dill, salt, black pepper and cooked rice, blending well.
Cover and cook, stirring occasionally, for 20 to 30 minutes longer or until vegetables are tender, adding shrimp the last 5 to 10 minutes.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Coronary Thrombosis Fudge
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100419516
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Sweet Treat
      </category>
      <description>
      As a long time favourite of the Turnbull Coronary thrombosis fudge is the
most potent chocolate attack on the tongue we've been able to concoct.
(This recipe was stolen from the internet... think we'd give out grandma's
secrets that easily?)
      </description>
      <spices>
      Sugar
Cocoa
      </spices>
      <source>
      null
      </source>
      <rating>
      Phenominal
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 Cup Butter
12 Ounces Semisweet Chocolate chips
1 jar Marshmallow creme
1 teaspoon vanilla extract
1 1/4 cups evaporated milk
4 cups white sugar
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Line a 13x9 inch baking dish with foil and butter the foil.
In the top half of a double boiler combine the butter or margarine, evaporated milk and sugar
Cook on medium heat for 12 mins or until a temperatur of 236 F is achieve.
Remove from heat and stir in the marshmallow creme.
Stir until chocolate chips milt into walnuts.
Spred the mixture into the prepared pan.
Score into squares while still warm.
Refrigerate until firm then cut along the scored lines.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Froot Loops avec Milk
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100815080
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Breakfast
      </category>
      <description>
      Made from exotic crunchy rings found only in grocery stores.
      </description>
      <spices>
      N/A
      </spices>
      <source>
      Loblaws, Metro
      </source>
      <rating>
      Awesome
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 (One) bowl Froot Loops
1 (One) bowl Milk
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Pour Froot Loops into bowl. Nibble on one or two.
Pour milk into bowl until overflow seems imminent.
Serve immediately, eat with spoon!
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Makhani Chicken (Indian Butter Chicken)
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      Sunniket Kundu, 100736285
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      Originally made in India a little before the invasion of the Bristish
empire. Now is known throughout the world for it's sweet or spiciness.
Per serving: 314 calories, 12 g total fat (4.8 g saturated fat), 33 g protein,
19 g carbohydrate, 4 g fibre, 120 mg cholesterol, 534 mg sodium
      </description>
      <spices>
      Chili Pepper
Cilantro
Cumin Seeds
      </spices>
      <source>
      http://www.foodnetwork.ca/recipes/Main/Chicken/recipe.html?dishid=8423
      </source>
      <rating>
      High
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      Tandoori Chicken
10 large boneless, skinless chicken thighs (about 21/4 lbs / 1.1 kg)
1/2 cup bottled Tandoori marinade (see Tip)
Butter Chicken Sauce
2 tablespoons butter
1 1/2 cups chopped onions
1 tablespoon minced garlic
1 1/2 tablespoons grated gingerroot
1 1/2 teaspoons chili powder
3/4 teaspoon ground turmeric
3/4 teaspoon ground coriander
1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon
1/2 teaspoon ground cumin
1 can (28 oz/798 mL) diced tomatoes, drained
1 1/2 cups reduced-sodium chicken broth
1 tablespoon brown sugar
1/4 teaspoon salt
1/4 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper
1/3 cup light sour cream (not fat-free)
1 tablespoon minced fresh cilantro
1 tablespoon cashew/almond butter (Tip)
Hot cooked basmati rice (optional)
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Tandoori Chicken
Poke raw chicken thighs in several places with a fork.
Place chicken in a large, heavy-duty, resealable plastic bag.
Add Tandoori marinade to bag.
Turn bag several times to coat chicken with marinade.
Marinate chicken in refrigerator for at least 6 hours or overnight.
Preheat oven to 425?F.
Place chicken thighs in a single layer on a baking sheet lined with foil and bake for 20 to 25 minutes, or until cooked through.
Do not overbake the chicken, or it will be dry.
When cool enough to handle, cut into bite-sized pieces and add to the butter chicken sauce as directed in recipe.
Butter Chicken Sauce
While chicken is baking, make sauce.
Melt butter in a large pot over medium heat.
Add onions and garlic. Cook slowly, stirring often, until onions are tender, about 5 minutes.
Add gingerroot, chili powder, turmeric, ground coriander, cinnamon and cumin. Cook 1 more minute.
Add drained tomatoes, broth, brown sugar, salt and pepper.
Reduce heat to low. Cover and simmer for 10 minutes, stirring occasionally. Remove from heat.
Transfer half the sauce to a blender and pur?e until smooth. Return pur?ed sauce to pot with remaining sauce.
Mix well and return to heat.
Stir in sour cream, cilantro and cashew/almond butter.
Add cut-up Tandoori chicken and mix well. Cook just until chicken is hot. Serve over hot basmati rice, if desired.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Scrambled eggs with tomatoes
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100673976
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Main dish
      </category>
      <description>
      This is me and my whole family's favorate dish. Very easy to cook and nutritious.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Tomatoes
Eggs
      </spices>
      <source>
      Not neccessary
      </source>
      <rating>
      Medium
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      Egg 3,
Tomato 150 grams,
Vegetable oil 4 soupspoon,
Salt,
monosodium glutamate
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      First,Cut the tomato into pieces.Then infiltrates the egg in the bowl, adds a little bit salt, evenly is ready to be used with the chopsticks full whipping. 3rd, 3 soupspoon oil to burn the heat, fry the egg in the pot and ready when it is ripely abundant. 4th, the surplus oil will burn the heat, put the tomato piece to stir-fry before stewing fries, puts the salt, the sugar fries the moment, will pour into the egg to turn fries several pots namely to become.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Carrot Salad
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100770031
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Side Dish
      </category>
      <description>
      Cold Salad.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Salt, Pepper, Dry Mustard
      </spices>
      <source>
      Family Recipe- Aunt
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 Carrots, sliced
1 large green pepper
1 large onion
1 cup sugar
1/2 cup vinegar
1 cup oil
1 can tomato soup
1 teaspoon dry mustard
1 teaspoon salt
1/2 teaspoon pepper
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Cook the carrots, drain and let cool. Add green pepper and onion. Combine soup and remaining ingredients. Pour mixture over carrots. Toss lightly and marinade overnight.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      French Onion Soup
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100780475
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Appetizer
      </category>
      <description>
      According to the legend of French onion soup, the recipe was invented or created by King Louis XV.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Salt and pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      Cooking Book
      </source>
      <rating>
      Not Spicy
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      3 Large red and sweet onions sliced finely
3 Tsp olive oil
1/4 Tsp sugar
2 Garlic cloves minced
8 Cups of beef broth
1/2 Cup white wine (dry)
1 Bay leaf
1/4 Tsp herb (preferably oregano or dry thyme)
8 Slices of toasted bread
2 Cups grated Parmesan and Gruyere cheese
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Heat olive oil in a thick-bottom pan, add onion and saute till they are caramelized but not burned. The flame should be medium high.
Add sugar and saute for 10 minutes more on a low flame. Once the onion is caramelized, add the minced garlic and saute for couple of minutes to remove the rawness. To it add the beef stock, white wine, bay leaf and the herbs. Simmer the flame and allow contents to cook for 20 to 30 minutes. Sprinkle salt and pepper to suit your taste. Remove the bay leaf from the soup. In a casserole, arrange the toasted bread slices. Pour the soup over it. Now sprinkle the grated cheese and bake for 10 minutes at 300 degree Fahrenheit or until the cheese melts. Serve hot..
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Squash Soup
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      100826935
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Side dish
      </category>
      <description>
      A nice light soup to compliment a main dish without being too overpowering or filling. If desired, this soup can be used as a main course quite nicely, however it requires a side to be a well rounded meal. An excellent source of vegetables this sweet and tangy soup is a delightful addition to any meal.
      </description>
      <spices>
      Thyme leaves
Salt
Pepper
      </spices>
      <source>
      Sister's Recipe Book
      </source>
      <rating>
      Mild
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      2 tbsp butter or margarine
1 medium onion, chopped
2 cloves garlic, minced
3 medium carrots, diced
2 stalks celery, diced
1 butternut squash, peeled, seeded and diced
1 medium potato, peeled and diced
3 cans chicken broth (use enough to just cover the vegetables)
1 tbsp honey
1/2 tsp tried thyme leaves
salt and pepper to taste
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      In a large pot melt butter over medium heat, stir in onion and garlic.  Cook and stir until lightly browned, about 5 minutes.  Stir in carrots and celery, cook until tender, about 5 minutes.  Stir in squash, potato, chicken broth, honey and thyme.  Bring mixture to a boil; reduce heat and simmer 30 to 45 minutes, or until vegetables are tender.  Remove from heat and cool slightly.  Working in small batches, transfer mixture to blender or food processor; process until smooth.  Return pureed soup to pot and season to taste with salt and pepper.  Heat until hot and serve.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

   <recipe>
      <recipe_name>
      Mrs. Fields Chocolate Chip Cookies
      </recipe_name>
      <contributor>
      #100789120
      </contributor>
      <category>
      Dessert
      </category>
      <description>
      These may or may not be the ultimate in chocolate chip cookies.  I'll give you a hint: they are.  For a little something to make their eyes go wide, consider adding a teaspoon of almond extract!
      </description>
      <spices>
      Vanilla
      </spices>
      <source>
      Mrs. Fields
      </source>
      <rating>
      Not spicy in the least.
      </rating>
      <ingredients>
      1 cup soft butter
1/2 cup sugar
1 1/2 cup brown sugar
2 eggs
2 1/2 tsp vanilla extract
2 1/2 cups all purpose flour
3/4 tsp salt
1 tsp baking powder
1 tsp baking soda
1 (12 oz bag) semi-sweet chocolate chip
      </ingredients>
      <directions>
      Cream butter and sugars together and then beat eggs and vanilla in.
Sift together dry ingredients and add to creamed mixture; stir well.
Fold chocolate chips and put golfball sized balls on an un-greased pan.
Bake @ 350oF for 7-9 min.    If cookies are not golden brown, continue baking for 2 min.
      </directions>
   </recipe>

</recipes_xml>
